Welcome to Tokyo 2020 and welcome to the wonderful world of table tennis.
I'm your commentator Adam Bobrow and we are getting in to the clash of the
Titans the match that we've been anticipating for the last five years. It is
world number one the most dominant player in the modern game at least in the
last few years. Shalpong little fatty Fon Jundong. Fon Jundong World ranked
number one. He's 24 years old the first seed and he's got quite a story a very
generous man played for the army team in China by E and had treated everybody
that showed up to a meal after they won but his opponent so much to be said
about arguably the greatest of all time the captain the dragon the dictator Ma
Long. Ma Long 32 years old world rank number three and spent more time at
world number one than anyone in the history of the sport 64 months he's the
defending gold medalist at the Olympics and I'm really excited to call this
match joining me my good friend former England team player 15 years as head
coach for the England team including three Olympic appearances as coach he's
smart he smells great and he's fun to be with Don Parker. Thanks Adam and we're
just deciding here spinning the coin who will serve who will play at Wichend
sort all that out the players are still in practice they'll go to their corners
now they'll have a last minute adjustments to their clothing it will probably be
no coaches in the corner China versus China looks as though that will be the
case and what a fascinating encounter the clash of the Titans it was referred to
and that's exactly what it is Fon Jundong their 24 years of age no doubt that
he's going to be massive star of the future but when is he going to
exert his authority I think that's the best way to put it over Ma Long Ma Long
arguably the best player of the last 50 years Janov Evoldner would be in my
opinion a challenger Janov Evoldner won the Olympic title lost very closely in
the final in Sydney nobody has won this Olympic men singles twice and if Ma Long
can win the gold medal tonight then I don't think many people could argue that
he's not being the best player of the recent times shall we say and there's a
gentleman who's gonna try and stop him Fan Chen Dong you know it's funny
that greatest of all time it's almost like an emotional decision for people
Waldner is my favorite player of all time he's just magic on the table but
statistically in terms of domination just the titles the records the absolute
domination over the rest of the world the win lost record against anybody in the
game for me there's no question about it with Ma Long but you're right I think
the only people if Ma Long were to win this gold medal who would still say
anything it would be 100% emotion and that's fine we can all have our favorites
but in terms of records Ma Long is unrivaled in the sport and as you
mentioned no one has ever taken two Olympic singles gold medals in the men's
side of the sport now this rivalry if anyone sees this is simply a China China
match oh there's just so much more on the line this is a juicy battle
Fan Chen Dong has shed more tears after pain pain stakingly difficult losses
where he was leading had match points arguably one of the best matches at
the last decade was the 2017 world championships men singles final and
Dusseldorf Germany between these two and I still get goosebumps every time I
rewatch it Ma Long stealing that match now just to talk about their games
Fan Chen Dong again way younger eight years younger let's look at who he's
being here Lebeson of France the freight train Marcos Freitas of Portugal
Jung Young chic for zero but had to save some game points and Lin Wun Roo in a
best of seven that came down to the decider he's the most explosive player in
the game Fan Chen Dong has quads like nobody's business quads for days
abs for weeks now on the other side the captain the dragon the dictator as
smooth and wise as can be he's so efficient took down Sharth Kamala Chanta the
Indian poster boy a table tennis the French showman Simon Gozi Omar Asar of Egypt
I saw it live in the stadium when Omar took a game off of Ma Long Omar Asar
playing some of the best table tennis of his life Urina Semi Zorova from Russia
our unpire now it's interesting because she's very I'd say consistently
strict on serves and that's her job is to keep things fair for the players now
Ma Long yesterday was called on serves will we see something here again at
the Olympics as the teammates from Shushin Wang Chuchin Ma Lin Olympic gold
medalist Chun Meng next to Liu Shuan the world champion Liu Goliang and Lee
Suin in the corner all watching very closely who are they supporting well team
China's flag will be raised after this but I think for table tennis
officianados the question is is the new generation here is the dictator ready to
be overthrown or will he hold down and put a nail in the coffin for the long
road trip conversation of the greatest of all time the umpire will be calling
the players to order very soon they're allowed two minutes pre-match practice
and indeed it's exactly what's happened we're just about to start what I'm
sure is going to be an absolutely thrilling gold medal match Ma Long the
current Olympic champion and indeed world champion he's won the last three
world championships the men's singles champion of the world three times back to
bike and he's now going for the double on the Olympic men's singles gold medal
so this will be a best of seven match first player to win four games games to
eleven must win by two and to start Xiaopang little fatty fun jundong back edge
of the table Ma Long with a bit of fortune to start surprise that he changed
his shirt color I heard a bit about the superstition within the Chinese
national team they tend to wear what's working for them stick with the same
color throughout the tournament and Ma Long wears a lot of red that
psychologically has been studied to be a winning color which is convenient for
a nation with a giant red flag that dominates the sport
and
leaping and jumping for that counter attack from behind the table this is only
just the first few points of the match but we know we're going to get a lot more
of this came from
look at that hooking side spin in a good six foot leap there
fun jundong still can't get a racket on it not a point dropped yet for captain
long
shorts side of the table on the step around full commitment much like the world
championship point and doseldorf interestingly enough in that match it was
studied and again the advantages to the player typically who takes the first
attack but Ma Long is so crafty so divisive that he'll give the first attack
as long as he sets it up well even to a player is powerful
is fun jundong world number one hand cake flip with the backhand
comes in with an open racket you think he's going to push it and then
turns his wrist over it usually he does it on the forehand but he's shown that he
can do it on both sides I mean deception right now absolute key control
that is ridiculous simply ridiculous to me the ball spills out on the table and he
pops it up to he took a guess here but what I guess if anticipated coming down
the foreign if you've gone the other way would have had no chance but it looks as
though the dictator is in fine form interesting to look at the heads to heads
15 five in favor of the gentleman on the screen you look at the last six
times that they've played for two to function don't and if you look at the
last time they played Ma Long was the winner so heads to heads it's close yeah
it's a very interesting setup for a while Ma Long was dominant he was about
13 and one fun jundong just couldn't break through it was like a spell that he
cast on fun jundong but in recent times as you mentioned fun jundong has
turned it around for winning record this isn't the start that the number one
said wanted seven love down just a little reminded that a recreational player is
out there there are no skunks in table tennis street play you can make
whatever rules you want but seven zero we've seen greater comebacks a little bit
off the top of the net to get on the scoreboard fun jundong has shown up to the
party fashionably dressed and fashionably late but it is a best of seven so we've
seen it already so many back and forths where someone dominates and then the
next game gets dominated table tennis always evolving even mid-match
very delicate short play there by both players that's what the top players can do
just delicately touch the ball and then all of a sudden particularly these two
explored with power on both wings
now in terms of both wings Ma Long favors the forehand a lot more than fun
jundong they both have very strong forehand backhand backhand fun jundong for
me has the stronger backhand but Ma Long's is so smart and well used it's a very
efficient divisive backhand sweat squad good to have you back what a good job
they've done here they're on an off the no time and the tables dry and the
players are ready to play calm have sweats on the table that's the motto actually
for sweatsquads team smart play short side hits it behind Ma Long
instead of going into that forehand cross-court shot the safer shot is to play
the length of the table but fun jundong taking a risk to keep it away from
Ma Long's counterattack he learned from his mistake earlier in the game that is
right
a little bit closer to the table here it's Ma Long staying closer the
efficient backhand long menu welcome to the picture in the upper right hand
corner at the second tile break here what are you thinking there's a lot of
Olympic champions in that team China they roll so deep it's crazy you Gugliang
was up there Ma Long was up there 96 winner 2008 winner a little game of
chicken they're protecting it both players trying to keep it just half long to
see if the other woman attacked first and when fun jundong finally snapped in
he made it count so a little bit slow out of the blocks function don't
but he's got himself going a little bit now but possibly a little bit too late for
this first game beautiful counter backhand generating a bit more topspin
adding to the topspin that was already on it chulae some say variety on the
cholae or chow different things that players shout and celebration to release air
and stress during tight moments six game points for the goat the dragon
Ma Long and a slower backhand does it changes the pace and dominates dictates
game number one again it's a best of seven and we've seen bigger twists and
turns will it be a question of mental focus preparation I think we're going to
get a lot more explosive power from fun jundong a sweat squad prepares us for
game number two coming up right after this
I've got into the rhythm of saying and now the players go back to their corner
for a tactical discussion but of course the players here without a coach it's
interesting that China take that option they do have their own coaches the
coaches they're associated with but if the China plays China then the players
are left to their own devices they have to think for themselves it's funny the
personal coaches over the years I know Chienji Jien has been working with Ma Long
for a long long time Wang Hao a three-time finalist at the Olympic Games had
27 months at world number one the best reverse pen hold backhand I've ever seen
and three silver medals and singles not so many Chinese players are even
allowed to play three Olympic singles a lot of questions about why you won't see
Lu Shouwen or Shushin playing but for those of you newer to the sport I will
simply say that the two grips that are most common in table tennis the
shakans grip much like you would shake someone's hand and then you use the last
three fingers to hold the blade to handle so both of these players are shakans
players a pen holder Shushin you'll have a chance to see in the teams event Ma Long
leading one zero starting with the serves coming in positive over the table a
good backhand out wide now the wide forehand I don't know I guess we didn't
tell the story this time around Ma Long had knee surgery not long ago and it
was a big decision for him he had a bit of a hold in his game to his wide
forehand but he looks faster and fitter now from this side angle you can
really see how crazy fast the light speed of the ball between these two again as
much as you might want to see a final with say Lin Wyn Ru or Dima battling
against one of the top two this is really the match between the two best that
are just a step above the rest of the world
to play Ma Long was just hanging around the backhand side of the table they're
looking to get his forehand in just see me steps to the left but then Feng Chen
Dong hits it wide to his forehand and of course the added bonus there the fight
that Ma Long knows he's gonna go wide to his forehand makes him less likely to
run around the backhand he's always worried about that ball catching him out
wide on his forehand there's the power the explosiveness of that backhand you
know it's funny again in the semi-finals I think most of the world wants to see
a challenge to the Chinese domination but I think we'd be robbed of the final
that we've all been waiting for if we didn't see these two battle it's really
just a battle of the generations that's been going on for a good part of the
decade now beautiful forehand flick up on one foot to play it over the table like
that finesse just taking you up on on that point there I I think it was great in
the semi-finals that we saw the Chinese these two players pushed to their
absolute limit so that's good for tables and it's and I also thought it was
good in the quarter finals we had four continents playing in the quarter
finals we had Africa we had South America obviously Asia and two players from
Europe so a spread of great players is wider people are pushing the Chinese a
little bit more but still we've got the finest two players in the world
slugging it out in this final and to be denied that would be very disappointing
right as a table tennis fan we're getting what we want here in props to
Africa the last two Olympic games making it to the quarter finals quadriaruna in
2016 in Omar Asar Tokyo 2020 it's a good sign Egypt and Nigeria battling for
supremacy in Africa and delivering some strong players nonetheless but
Fongen Dome with the serves here tied up at the first towel break much better
start in game one he comes out fired up a bit now it's interesting in terms of
respect via age almost everybody on the Chinese national team and asked who
their hero is they say brother long it's Ma Long and for Fongen Dome I think
just the rivalry alone they're obviously good friends but I think he can't say
out loud because he needs to fight his hardest
also good back I'm from Ma Long out wide to Fong Chen Dome's forehand
interestingly enough Wang Hao many suspect might be Fong Chen Dome's favorite
favorite player who's also been working with him as a personal coach so it's
nice to have your hero sort of training you over the years in terms of coaches
Wu Jinping who trained Lu Guo Liang trained Ma Lin Xu Xin also trained Fong Chen Dome for the young age
currently working with Fong Tian Wei interestingly enough clever placement there
from Ma Long just that area where you're not sure whether to play a backhand or
forehand I think clever is a word that can apply to Ma Long throughout he's just
so brilliant like next level IQ on the table he can always find an answer even
for a player as strong and seemingly flawless as Fong Chen Dome quick on his
feet then what an angle with that forehand topspin it's so compact that backhand
he's able to generate so much strength I'd say that flicker the wrist I mean he's
a really solid guy I've physically bumped into him before and I will tell you this
man is a rock
in terms of belief you know table tennis is such a mental game I think having that
belief throughout sort of like when Lu Guo Liang shouted to Ma Long last night
against Dima he can't beat you he cannot beat you I think that's what Fong Chen Dome
has to be thinking right now every single point know that this is very possible
after all he's won four there last six encounters how much of that do you think is
for himself and how much of you of that do you think was for Ma Long bit of both I
think that he's trying to pump himself up and he was well beaten in the first game
he's got himself pumped up he's playing he's now in the swing of things and there is
this definite trying pose yourself on your opponent final of in one of the world
championships Chang Ji Liang marched around the table when he was playing
Voldner walked all the way around the circle full circle and I asked him I
commented with him once he was in the next booth and I asked him about that he said
I was letting him know that was my table that was my and that was that was what
was in Chang Ji Liang's mind marking his territory we are animals developed
ones opposable thumbs and some other stuff but man the animal is still very much
present here I love it
oh short side of the table on the counter racket head up quickly in Ma Long
again another high IQ quick play I have to play against somebody who seems to
know the future
perfect placement into the middle still almost comes down we've seen points like
this where the ball comes back over the net which is why Ma Long was there
following the ball you do not have to hear I'm gonna crush an urban myth for you
in table tennis or ping pong you do not have to stay on your half of the table
if the ball comes back over the net you can run around and hit it backwards
towards where it came you can actually even jump on the table in table tennis
you just can't put your free hand on the table interesting her good length
here funggen don't keeping it short enough that it stays over the table Ma Long
right at the back edge trying to get that full swing the full stroke now there's a
lot to talk about equipment too a professional racket is enough to get anybody
excited about the sport for me that's what got me hooked learning how to spin the
ball feeling the trampoline the catapult the both of these players are playing
with but by the time you get to their level the specifics matter a lot and
those hard Chinese rubbers are very tacky very heavy and take a lot of strength
to lift and swing spinny return from funggen don't long
not quite getting over the ball probably be coming out on top on the back
out to back on rallies as Ma Long but not on that occasion which is also a bit
surprising just because from a power standpoint I mean back hands I think if you
had to construct your own player you picked different features maybe you picked
the backhand of funggen don't maybe pick the brain of Ma Long along with every
other skill set oh speaking of clever here funggen don't season turning early and
says nah no you don't watch this quick step around you like other way and
regrets I think we got the close up of that facial reaction there two game points
now for the 24 year old world number one funggen don't soft for a moment and
then the fireworks come out the fast play and it is Ma Long wow it looks like
Ma Long has got this point funggen don't one more time here that wasn't far off
the one that missed was close from funggen don't 10 9 1 game point remains he has the
serve definite advantage for funggen don't the pancake flip killed you could hear the
smacking sound as he spanked that ball off to the corner naughty ball you've misbehaved
in Ma Long is gonna set things right start open and then just on contact flips these
wrist flicks through the back of the bowl so deceptive tough to get prepared for so here we are at
doose in game number two strong backhand from funggen don't exactly what we've been talking about
just taking a while for him to get as strong as that to plays backhand as strong as that but he seems
a lot more relaxed now on the backhand side third game point now for funggen don't let 10 8 and he
now leads 11 10 to the dead in sweat squad sweat squad out nope right back gotta take care of them both
I mean two of the best in the game the two players who were cut above the dotted line game point
funggen don't third time over on the move finds a placement wide to the forehand testing the
footwork of Ma Long who loves to step around the backhand but he's gonna have some hesitation with
that reminder of what funggen don't can do to the wide forehand so tied up now one game a piece
this could be a seven game extravaganza and I'm sitting here with my imaginary popcorn thinking
please give us seven games how you feeling right now well I'm thinking the two semi-finals with
seven games the bronze medal match was seven games so why shouldn't the goldmatch be seven games I
100% agree with your logic and this prediction of the future would be very nice so we'll have our
fingers crossed here just assault I like to think that second game yeah I think Funshan don't
looking good and I just thought if he loses this second game we could see Ma Long two nilup and
funggen but I think now if I was predicting which I'm not very good at but I think Funshan don't
now it's one or anybody's but I just seem to think Funshan don's moving better is playing a bit
more confident on the backhand let's see well you know head to head I think I've been asked this
question a lot too and it's not a question of what we want it's a question of what we think
sometimes just honesty is opposed to wishful thinking but I can't disagree with you on this either
way mentality matters for sure so does experience on the grand stage and it's different again with
less people in the crowd but Ma Long has played the Olympic gold medal match before and there's
more on the line than just the gold medal I mean if funggen don't win this he could not only get
two singles gold medals but maybe a third in his career the cracking backhand goes just long
spectacular play and he hits it behind the momentum into the pocket of Ma Long from behind the
table funggen don't really I've seen him bend like you wouldn't believe in how far back his
forehand pulled for that opening shot so much racket speed again his arm even in the slow
mo replay was just a blur so tied up at one point a piece serves back with the dragon
clever idea good anticipation this time Ma Long is learned to look for that quick backhand on
the parallel by the way in case you were curious about where the term dragon comes from the word
in Chinese Ma Long's given name actually means dragon his full name is horse dragon sounds nice
are in Chinese though turned again and burned again burning and turning it is funggen don't
on the other side of the table who's very quick to know the patterns of brother long his predecessor
and he moves back well to right I mean that balls deep to the corner when he plays it what's
interesting is did he same move or did he anticipate he moving these are I think he saw him I think
he saw him I think he just saw it out of the corner of his eye and he switched and I think it
might be a combination of both I think he might be ready for it and then you're right the visuals
there the peripheral look how close to the table his legs completely under the table look how big
his quads are to support him in that while he's under the table and still over with the racket
again quads and core strength table tennis muscles
oh gonna see more of those chop blocks I love him when he just drops the guillotine on that backhand
side and under spin Ma Long actually one of the most consistent at pulling off the chop block I
would say him koki niwa and port the ricos adriana Diaz takes incredible feeling and hand
controlled to be able to do that could serve followed in behind the serve with a strong top
spin dominated the rally Ma Long have you ever seen someone wearing a Ma Long Jersey walking
around wearing one that said Ma Long on the back can't say I have I have I thought it looked amazing
I bring that up because I remember for years just thinking you know we've got basketball culture
people wearing LeBron James jerseys if you had a Ma Long Jersey with gold lettering on the back and
you wore it on the street I would immediately look up to you I'd be jealous just saying four points
a piece here dead even two superstars in the clash of the Titans for the gold medal battle in game three
not enough height was the warning on the serve I love how fondsendong handles he's so humble just
is okay sorry sorry I'll make the adjustment after all that's what he's got to do to stay focused
don't want to feel like you're having an argument with someone who's not involved in playing against
you here
it's interesting how we saw in the bronze medal match
Hofcheroff was fouled took a point off him straight away no warning I think it's sensible to give
a warning unless it's a very bad error it is common it is definitely common must have been
pretty clear to the umpire at the time what a dance I was watching the way fondsendong moved and
got his racket up for the forehand to cover the elbow in that rally but then the next time it came
back right to that same spot the elbow he chose to play backhand I've talked about Ma Long's
mentality at a tournament he's the nicest guy a teddy bear off the table but a monster on
and at tournaments he focuses he's got this mom of mentality just completely tunnel vision
clever serve long and fast well placed down the middle of the table
this serves it's a little bit lukewarm sits up a little bit high something in between and
fondsendong was exactly what to do with this free shot it bounced too high as well
needs to go low and fast that one just a little bit too bouncy pumped up so much credit to Lin
Wyn Roof for being able to serve Long so consistently and cause trouble it's not an easy
serve to do with this level the handshaking there good placement Ma Long leaving it just behind
the net short on the backhand says I dare you and try to play that down the line good luck
the most exciting thing about this is I have no idea how it's going to finish
but crazy stuff is going to happen subtle adjustments throughout tactically from both of these players
very slow probably that neither play taking the initiative
it's funny Ma Long reminds me of the Muhammad Ali of table tennis he's not afraid to just let the
opponent swing does I'm comfortable where I am you do what you have to do here's a ball go for it
so it happened in 2017 at the world champs again take the first shot I'll let you hit me first
what a counter the long push into Ma Long's body was surprising but he adjusts and then a parallel
backhand from fondsendong and Ma Long's right there to counter back on the wide forehand just keep
in the hands cool three point lead two points away from a two to one advantage in games
too strong that receive very quick to play it right at the back edge of the table and to the
wide corner as well just drifted long the service it just allowed funsendong to play away from the
table ideally with the short serve you try and make your opponent play over the table
that chop block was nasty but fondsendong with the footwork gets around and pounds it deep to the
backhand corner now this is interesting normally when there are no coaches in corners we see time
out later in the match does this mean that Ma Long could end up being a coach in the future when
he's retired and hangs up all his accolades hopefully it's no time soon we've got the world
championships in November in the United States and I know the world would love to see Ma Long
there but this for me is a very mature time out here in game three well the one thing for sure with
Ma Long he's got a great table tennis brain and therefore that will be very helpful from the
coaching point of view he would clearly have the respect of the top players arguably the greatest
player in recent times so yeah but I agree let's let's not push him into coaching let's keep
him playing the game for as long as he can it's a pleasure to actually watch him play always a
master class now for those of you curious about the time out oh yeah it came up the other day
1997 the time out was invented in table tennis it was not part of the game until 1997 so interestingly
enough that's the majority of my competing years so it always felt like it was there but Ma Long
had a 96 lead knows how important it'll be to keep the authority the dictatorships so to speak
over Fongendol just having that mental edge and Fongendol with two points here is dangerously
close he's breathing on the back of the neck of the dragon so Ma Long despite being on the receive
is going to have to come up with a plan and that's why he took that minute to do a bit of brain
storming soul searching we'll see how he receives this second serve of world number one the top
seed Fongendol and there it is patient play just touch for touch until the ball comes long and Ma Long
at the back of the table able to brush up waiting for it that's the one and I love how Ma Long
sweeps the right leg just to get it out of the way for that full stroke and then he creates this
really stable stance in the middle of that rally so two game points here for Ma Long to take a two-to-one
lead oh the spinney sneaks it past him what a quick crazy shot Ma Long on the back hand corner
of the table sees an opportunity and seizes that opportunity wasn't that long he was able to
get in with that full hand top spin and it was below the net too this is what top spin is all about
there are no straight lines that will go through that ball and make it on the opponent side of the
table so he adds a whirlwind of spin to it so it arcs up and stays low to the net still and drives
right past Fongendol so a two-to-one lead Ma Long the defending gold medalist again never in
history has any man won two gold medals and singles at the Olympic Games in Ma Long right now
in a better position to do it than anybody in history has been
rehydrated Fongendol meanwhile left court side to change his shirt sort of dehydrating his shirt
it'd be funny if he actually changed into a shirt and then poured a water bottle on it
so it just felt like it was broken in already changing into a sweaty or shirt
fascinating decision probably unlikely though it was tough to read the lips of Ma Long as he
was talking to himself there with this water bottle before but he always has that hotel looking
towel that full-size shower towel there
so now we have a few words with himself that
he'll be popping with the situation too on up I would love to know exactly what he said
again I think if he was speaking to another human being we'd have a better chance at a
lip read but I think it's just extra time here because Fongendol went to change his shirt
again cultural humility here saying I'm going to step outside to change shirts
there is a term icing the kicker sometimes from time to time you'll see players stop and tie
their shoe that I guess Vladi actually who recently retired the evergreen Vladi Mir Samson
obviously Timo Bol in the crowd among some other table tennis officianados and coaches
but I was going to say they're of Ladi I think got guarded once for not asking permission
either to tie his shoe or to clean up some sweat with the towel you are supposed to communicate
with the umpire whenever you take an out of turn extra bit of time and quick shout out to our
assistant umpire from Japan Satocho sue oshi again the best umpires in the world here
only the best to officiate Masahiro and the crowd myehada of Japan has done incredible
things for table tennis in Japan the second biggest market market for table tennis sorry sorry
got a tuck in the shirt excuse me there's something funny about this that maybe it's just that
he's at center court and it's I don't know he's a very childlike kind adorable person but a monster
on the table a little bit off the top of the net but good surprise placement for me from Marlon
what do you think about that point I think Marlon he's making the countertops things really well
he's feeling the ball really well he's tactically probably on top here if he just gets I think he
gets him with the first strong top and keeps on top in the rally then having tipped him and now
thinking don't tip against Marlon you made him angry he's just a legend he heard you
I don't feel I don't feel too bad doing that because I think Fengshan Dong is just a great player
as well we just got two great players out there nothing wrong with looking at stats and forming
a educated guess that said not a point dropped yet by the dragon I'm surprised that he's still
stepping around we've seen him take some early steparounds for that forehand on the backhand corner
with lengthier Fengshan Dong leaving it right here the back edge Marlon says I want nothing to do with
you new ball please see a bit of frustration in Marlon for missing that shot knowing the difference
sort of the mind control of having a 4-0 flawless start that was a great return came across a little
bit to play backhand from the middle of the table got a wonderful angle out wide tomorrow's
fall and there he's there he goes can't get much more corner than that and as deep and fast as can be
smart play the forehands to me I know the backhand finished the point but Marlon is able to play
these counter forehands with such short strokes again it was the time to stop backhand these the
one down the line here he comes look at that forehand though the first forehand there was almost no
backswing and just sort of Marlon creates a triangle with his left arm he holds it out in front
and the backhand just meets it to complete the triangle
this is the battle that Fengshan Dong wants if he can get into the backhand to backhand battle with
Marlon keep him from stepping around or at least allow him to step around deep to open up the
parallel backhand and test Marlon on the wide forehand that said he came back from down 0-3 is one
three of the last four points and now has a second serve to continue his momentum
smart play right back to where it came from
the lesson there to anybody you know who's hoping to play at a high level is you've got to play
down the lines and that's what these great players do play on the diagonal play into the body but they
go down the line and so many points can be won by moving the ball around but going down the line
and if you're new-rated table tennis the reason is cross-court is the safest shot it's the length of
the table the hypotenuse if you will that'll be my last geometry reference for the next 30 seconds but
down the line takes a lot of practice because there's less margin for air
yet he does it again Marlon pins in with that parallel forehand right down the line
congratulations again Chunmeng World No. 1 for a few years taking the gold medal last night
pretty epic women's battle between her and Shasha Shinging Shah
oh that was nice next time will be a yellow card a warning for a warning that's very generous
the warning was delay of game no stalling both of these players have a lot to consider
we've actually seen this on the world tour for years when it's two players from the Chinese national
team in the final really being thoughtful and taking their time between points
the angle the side spin that ball is devastating
take another look here quick pancake flip from the backhand and that side spin that he gets on it
just hitting the outside of the ball the way he wraps around and pulls it back to nearly behind
his head secures him the point
that's a great shot Fun-shin Dong was trying to touch it short didn't quite manage it didn't
quite have the feeling the push went long and I'm not just puts so much power into the shot starts
with these legs rotation of the upper body shoulder elbow wrist he's looking so stable right now
that's second to last shot that he did from the backhand corner I mean you couldn't tell where he
was going to go until he actually went there and of course that's too late he was down low the safe
shot would have been cross-court and he still manages to spin it down the line fun-shin Dong
in some trouble now crucial point if he wants to turn things around oh deep on the table covers
the middle with the racket head straight up I thought Ma Long had him jammed it's a very
unconventional shot at this level yeah if you could see you could see Dong in that moment
it just almost looked like like kids playing just sort of slapped back at it with the racket up
that's the way I was going to use he slapped it by
there are these subtle little things to demonstrate feeling that the players do between points
that are actually quite impressive into them it's just like nothing
good placement wide enough to cause trouble it's a it's almost like stretch arm strong Ma Long
is able to get an extra few centimeters reaching like he loosens up his shoulder to make sure he can
get his racket on the ball for that wide forehand so two quick points from Fong and Dong was able
to convert both of his serves suddenly this game could go either way big serve here for the dragon
all the hits the back-out chop spin three game points from Ma Long that was so impressive to me
because the ball was shallow it was soft when it was hit to Ma Long he moves in slows down
and gives a spinny ball back it's almost creepy how much he's able to manipulate the ball
three game points from Ma Long
oh
oh changed his mind decided to go for a long push from the baseline of the table which is always
tricky it's a good receive by Fong and Dong
Fong and Dong now has these two serves to come
last time he did he won him both so at the third towel break again for those of you just joining
us towel breaks every six points allowed also if someone serves at low to the net
and it goes into play it's called a let serve and that can happen in infinite amount of times
in theory
well pressure from the back of the table Fong and Dong in position tests the forehand and Ma Long
tries boldly to go down the line but two game points saved no timeouts left for Ma Long
when we have those short pushing rally short touch shots it seems to be the one who gets him
with the first top spin generally wins the point
oh what a finishing shot devastating the Chiquita the banana flick from Fong and Dong comes
right into the elbow and Ma Long does not blink he does not flinch he just raises the rack
getting hooks it back and like a hurricane show lay the ball is gone with the wind
so sweat squad cleans the table as we come back for game five but this is interesting I mean
we talk about pushes we talk about short game we talk about wisdom experience patience
parallel shots this man has it all you can ask the legends of the game and they call him the
most complete player they've ever seen yet still his job is not done yet by the way for those
of you newer to the sport a push is a short shot it's a more defensive play where a player puts
backspin or under spin on the ball to keep the opponent from attacking and we do see long pushes
where someone will try to jam the opponent Ma Long's pulled out almost everything so far
but I wonder I know Fong and Dong has done it before he's come back from down even
against Ma Long I don't know if he's come back from this much down there
what do you think we're going to see change wise from Xiao Pong little fatty
I think he's got to look to try and get in with the first strong topspin I'm trying
dominate the rally Ma Long's very good at the counter topspin so placement of the ball into the
body wide either side but I do think the one who makes the first strong topspin
has got a good chance of going on to win the point not every time because they're so good at the
counter topspins got a light in the background maybe could a bit of door open ball kit in the court
wait gate open I think one of the ball boys must be just standing a little bit too far into the court
that's the back counter backhand Fong and Dong very strong in that department
I feel like he took a page out of the tactical book of Ma Long here
Ma Long's been playing occasionally he chooses a step around for the forehand but he's been
covering the middle of the table quite well so he first strong topspin wins the point
good start by Fong Qian Dong he needed to start strong he has three games that are all must win
if he's going to take this Olympic gold medal
no no no you cannot these players it's unbelievable Ma Long jumping to rip that backhand he's got
the team applauding as well inside out forehand countered by Fong and Dong still blocks it back
look at the flexibility the waist of Fong and Dong it's amazing to me that his torso doesn't come off
cover spinny forehand topspin from Ma Long there let the ball drop and then he brushed up the back
of the ball if you brush the ball then the speed of the racket is converted into spin if you go
through the ball then you get the pace yeah for me that was just such a determining point because
it reminds Fong and Dong that almost nowhere is safe and then he finds a place he finds it quickly
this time opening up with the parallel you know you talked earlier about the touch the push game
in the hands of these players they've both done things that are mind blowing with soft shots
Fong and Dong had a ball go viral a few years back hitting it under the net clamp for a roller on the table
whether you're a table tennis fan or not you probably saw it just because well the whole world
saw it was one of those shots that the reactions of the opponents Simone Gozi and Fong and Dong
himself I mean the whole stadium looked up at the giant screen just to watch the replay about four
times hashtag sweat squad I see you so Fong and Dong cleaning that top sheet of rubber just fogging
it up for a moment so that he gets full traction and grip on that forehand spin two serving four
so a good start here from world number one in blue Fong and Dong leading at the first towel break
homie a gay a gift liu
what says off the end of the table
it's good that he's not afraid at this point to take risks but that is the risk
you have to keep it baseline and fast if you're going long he knows that well
interesting score line here the other interesting thing I think it because these two plays are so
quick on the feet that when they go for the angles whichever angle it is wide to the foreign
wide to the backhand they're putting side spin on it we'll try to take it even wider and that makes
it more difficult I love the coverage of the middle with the forehand right now from Fong
and Dong how many times can you recall him in this game alone just leaning his upper body out of
the way and playing across the inside of the ball for the forehand they have this remarkable ability
it must come from the hours and hours of training when they're leaning when they're twisting when
they're off balance they still play with power oh sharp block attempted and it was fast it was a
vicious chop block indeed it was but it didn't come off healthy situation for the number one seed
but he is three one down check in the rubbers just to see if the contact was there so he's
cleaning it again you know we talk about the physical strength the conditioning my long one said
back in the day his only enemy his injury he had no fears simply injury so he works incredibly hard
oh man smoke down the line geez would you like that medium rare well well done Fong and Dong quick
turn right to the corner just a blink of an eye and you miss that one the speed from such a short
stroke it's like the Bruce Lee one inch punch who happens to be his favorite actor Bruce Lee
well he's certainly been positive this game he certainly looked to take the initiative when he can
and he's leading ten three
top swing down the line attempted chop block from my long and a very comfortable fifth game for
the number one seed eleven points to three
so this spices things up a bit a little bit of pepper added to the pot now to see what will
actually turn out as these two stir up some crazy delicious points to be played ahead sweat squad
so careful and always on point it's interesting I feel like in table tennis at this level yes of course
power is important but the players with the most power don't necessarily make the best players
there's so many ingredients and Fong and Dong in the early parts of his career I mean he started
beating world-class players at sixteen years old I think he took his first title fifteen sixteen
and he just always seemed like he was at volume ten like he was always turned up for power but when
it came to short play my long was able to just find his buttons and just make him make him regret
moving earlier change it up but his game has developed a lot and that's part of the reason we
see Fong and Dong I mean how many times do you have to be in a locker room crying because someone's
stole a match from you that you were so close to getting before you find some answers Thomas Bach
IOC president in the crowd always nice to see that what an honor really for the sport also
Olympic gold medalist Yu Sung Min think president of the Korean Table tennis association now
and Omar Asar was there from Egypt the quarter finalist who took a game off of Ma Long and played
the best table tennis I've seen in my life from Omar Asar he's got a bright future ahead of him
pretty cool section to be able to see there in the crowd huh a lot of Olympic champions out there
it's nice they can get everybody back in together
it's interesting of the gold medals that China have dropped 35 34 and they've won
I think they've dropped five gold medals out of the 35 and they've dropped three of them in men's singles
you namq won the first in 88 folder one in 92 in Barcelona and Ru Sung Min who we just saw one in
2004 in Athens so they've lost to mixed doubles and they've lost to women's doubles
yes the five gold medals they've dropped a remarkable record I don't think a country's dominated
a sport quite like China doing table tennis maybe there is but I can't think of one
and I'm with you there so a bit of momentum for the top seat who's down firing himself up right
now at the top of the screen Fong Jendong down two to three Ma Long one game away
what a recovery there the top of the net and he just calmly guides it back like nothing ever
happened I mean that can be a wrench in the system a net ball during a fast rally
I think Fong Jendong will be disappointed to have missed that one I think he always out of the
blocks is Ma Long he's flying I'm just shaking my head here because that ball he may look easy
but he's outside the table pulls everything together the core strength to play that perfectly into
the elbow of his opponent so Fong Jendong in better position here a little closer to the table
gets Ma Long a step behind from this bird's eye view you'll have a chance to see well guess it
might have just been camera angle but played it more shallow in front of Ma Long
I love the fire that's lit inside both of these guys right now I mean this is the dream
Ma Long it would surprise me if we get to see him playing another Olympic games and as we
talked about before this would be just icing on the cake for the greatest of all time conversation
what miss by a fair margin it's really interesting isn't it look at how Chinese players have
progressed they tend to retire a little bit earlier than you know we've got Vladimir Samson
of playing at 45 we've got Timo ball playing at 40 and he shall be ended 58 but very few of the
Chinese men go be at 32 it'll be 36 at the next Olympics I can't see my own way in although
a hat trick of men singles titles if he can win this he's still got a fair bit of work to do here
but three two up of course on terms of hat tricks for gold singles medals Fong Jendong's 24 will
play another one in three years likely he has a chance to be playing his third men singles final
younger than Ma Long is right now so that would be massive Ma Long looking to take this big time
right here right now and this is the thing with the greatest of all time it's only up to this
point in time time out here for Fong Jendong I say that because if Ma Long does take this gold medal
it would be crazy the Ma Long fan club which is amazing and massive would be thrilled but Fong
Jendong could still equal the records that Ma Long has taken in his career it was 2015 for me the
world championships in Sujo where Ma Long found this confidence to really just close the door on
everybody else in big competition he spent 34 months at world number one he was just dominant and
from 2012 through 2017 had nearly five years without losing a single match to a foreigner
and that's the biggest offense when you play for China it's a very patriotic proud nation
and rightly so but for losing to a foreigner is the only thing that is unacceptable
yeah I think it's a really interesting debate isn't it of course China can't play China when
it's the team event you don't have to play Chinese players old and I have to play the Chinese
players in every team event that he played in and he have to consistently beat them whereas Ma Long
only plays only plays Fong Jendong in singles so that there are good arguments backwards and
forwards but for sure for me if Ma Long is two times Olympic champion the debate is over
he is the greatest and he's not far from doing it he's minutes away from potentially doing it
let's see and it does not come down on the table edge of the racket big point out of the time
out here I'd love the debate just because I think it's interesting but we'll wait and see
I think still Ma Long against his Chinese teammates has the most dominant the best record against
the Chinese of anybody period if you compare it with Waldener's record against the Chinese still
Ma Long is by far the most dominant
tight pendulum served to the short forehand again the pendulum served the first time anyone learns
a professional serve almost always it's the pendulum serve yet the greatest of all time as we're
discussing uses this serve still so that serve you can never perfect it
still alive and kick and Fong Jendong turns the backhand corner with some power
very narrow margin here just two points again both of these players have pulled off crazy
comebacks even against each other with bigger deficits and differences in the score
that said it is a very interesting point you bring up about who Waldener had to play in team
events noted
shot block pays off the first time we've seen the chop block come out and win him the point
outright just a little less in here and how it's done heavy spin side and under but mostly side
there for Ma Long and so it's over lifted that's the tricky part about the chop block is that
it's a combination of two spins and you're not sure how much of which ingredient is in it
all the full hand down the line that was fast and furious Ma Long sets him up so well speaking of
Tokyo drift check this out short shot and the power full extension there on that forehand and it
pays off four points in front now Ma Long three points away from the nail in the coffin
you'll have to find something else to talk about table tennis fans another road trip table tennis
conversation but not lying down he will not make this easy he will not go down without a fight
so far over an hour already in this match
second serve here for the dragon
and a big forehand on the step round he silently celebrates to himself but knows that he cannot take
his mind off this match the moment he starts thinking about a gold medal he blurs his focus and
fondge and don will creep back in second serve in this sequence coming up most swim point
my mouth isn't very good there is he got two serves to come
you're just ahead of your time you said it right here it is the second serve in the sequence for
fondge and don't i was just late to catch on to what you already knew nine plus five four
teen even number two serves to come basic basic maths i like it six serving nine
oh the line misses ever so slightly it is four gold medal points to just absolutely cement the
goat the greatest of all time and the serves are on his side to do it
oh not yet fondge and don't spring it with that backhand a fearless shot
how do you convince yourself that the scoreboard is zero zero when you're playing against the
gold medal point lily-john getting video of this three gold medal points left second gold
medal point here for Ma Long on his serve he does not want to end up on the receive in this match now
and he does it Ma Long takes it the heart he gives his love to the world the captain the dragon the
dictator the greatest of all time has done the unthinkable standing ovation from the crowd
no man in Olympic history has ever taken two gold medals and Ma Long was 64 months at world
number one has shattered every record in table tennis history you are looking at the greatest
of all time delete the word arguably this man has done it he has shimha said that is hello and welcome
to the victory ceremony you're watching Tokyo 20 it's been the wonderful world of table tennis
the best players in the world just battled for the medals but from the semi finals on there is no
question we got every single cent we spent to enjoy the thrills spills turns and twists of this event the men's
singles so as the medalists come out in the front you see Fon Jendong following behind him Ma Long
behind him Dimitri Ovtarav Dima
and just like in the women's battle you wish that you could give out four medals because everyone
played so well from the semi finals on there is no question that this was an epic men's singles
event at Tokyo 2020 while he will not be here a shout out to Lin-Winru search him on YouTube he's
incredible but these three were the best in the men's singles event and we will start off by honoring
our second time bronze medalist from Germany
on the right we have Mrs. Sarah Walker IOC member Akili from New Zealand and Olympian
took a silver medal IOC news and Olympian
interestingly enough gets to wear a gold medal right now that's pretty cool
and the ITTF executive vice president from Sweden Mrs. Petra Surling I've had a chance to play
table tennis with her actually she's been a strong advocate and a hard worker to develop the sport
over the last along before I was involved at this level so a long time a lovely person and a
deep passionate heart for table tennis she's still playing actually which is quite exciting
and our bronze medalist playing the best table tennis I've seen from him in his life
Dimitri Ovtrav Dima of Germany once again an Olympic bronze medal bringing pride to Deutschland
East Leave a Teesh tennis I love table tennis there is no question that Dima carries on a family
tradition both of his parents coaches must be incredibly proud and interestingly enough a father
to Emma him and Jenny Ovtrav both table tennis players and a very proud moment for the Ovtrav
family the hard work has paid off through injury through thick and thin he stands here today
in the silver medalist people's Republic of China
and our silver medalist world number one Xiaopang little fatty fun jundong
fun jundong has been incredible for the last several years and holds up his silver medal with pride
as dominant as he's been in the game there's only one player who could stop him here he's got an
incredibly bright future ahead and I would not be surprised to see him with a gold medal around
his neck three years from now but a wizard on the table a brain like no other the man the captain
the dragon the dictator with love will stand in front of the world on the top podium here he is
two-time Olympic gold medalist a world record never has it been done before the greatest of all time
Ma Long proudly wears the gold medal for the second time in his career and for the first time in
history we have witnessed a raising of the bar at the Olympic Games this will not happen for a long
time maybe in your lifetime you will see it but a record that will be very difficult to break
Ma Long the three-time and defending world champion three consecutive time has two consecutive
gold medals and now the most famous national anthem in table tennis no matter where you are please
stand for the Chinese national anthem
so what a crowd there on screen again the Chinese national team the superstars of the sport
and the masks are off the smiles are out I think Fong Gen Dong might not be the smile that you
would hope to see in a very humble smile for Ma Long taking it easy wow so much charm and you
don't get to see that face again it's the mamba mentality so many athletes have inspired Ma Long
and he will inspire countless athletes for decades to come from YouTube videos to television shows
the table tennis spectacle that he's brought to the sport we can only hope and cherish the
moments that we have your grass cough that thumbs up and team O'Bull for the last two decades has
been one of the few to challenge the Chinese but here at the Olympic Games the tournament that
Dima has been able to deliver in in 2012 now again in 2021 at Tokyo 2020 they wear their flags
proudly on their face and bring medals home to their nations two of the biggest table tennis
nations in the world loot Wollion with two thumbs up change a gen behind him just the same least
swing huh shall Wang Manu behind along with Olympic gold medalist Chun Meng who last night left
a giant footprint in history but no footprint as big as the one Ma Long has created for China here
at Tokyo 2020 table tennis a year round sport if you're just getting into it now welcome to the
wonderful world of table tennis it's magical year round you don't want to miss it so be sure to follow
all the table tennis you can on the internet on TV will this man get a fourth world champion chip
title as well in Houston in November I don't know but what I do know is right now there is no
question that Ma Long is the greatest table tennis player there ever was while he stands tall and proud
he kisses the gold medal he said before this tournament started if he loses a single game he will have
let down China and he hasn't dropped a single match everything has been one undefeated once again
just like in Rio 2016 which gave the nickname to his son Mario fans nicknaming his son
the after